我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is barry allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
And I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
But secretly, with the help of my friends at s.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
我让杀害母亲的凶手自食其果
I hunted down the man who killed my mother,
但我们的世界也因此出现了新的威胁
but in doing so, I opened up our world to new threats,
我是唯一来得及阻止他们的人
And I am the only one fast enough to stop them.
我叫闪电侠
I am the flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously, on "The flash"...
这就是你来中城的原因吗
Is this why you came to central city?
这些不好的东西
This nonsense.
但我真心没必要对你解释什么
I don't actually have to explain myself to you.
这是违法的  我是警察
This is illegal. I'm a cop.
一个不知道自己还有个儿子的警探
The detective who didn't know he had a son.
我今天去看妈妈了
I saw mom today.
她说你有些日子没去看她了
She says you haven't been by in a while.
她觉得是因为你在生她的气
She thinks it's because you're angry with her.
我有理由生气
I have every right to be angry.
-我要离开中城  -什么
- I'm leaving central city. - What?
我被米德韦城市大学的
I was accepted into the forensic science program
鉴证科录取了
at midway city university.
已经把乌龟人关起来了
Got turtle locked up in the pipeline.
现在要做的就是想个办法偷走极速的速度
All we got to do is use him to figure out how to steal
然后我们把你的女儿救回来
Zoom's speed, and then we'll get your daughter back.
时间估计比我们想像的要长
That might take longer than we thought.
因为乌龟人死了
Because turtle's dead.
现在做出决定
Now, decide in return
以换回你女儿的性命
for your daughter's life.
我会帮你偷闪电侠的速度
I will help you steal the flash's speed.
哈德逊屋顶焦油厂
人们现在认为焦油只是用来涂房顶的
People think of tar now as mainly a roofing product.
两年前
有趣的是
Fun fact.
它还被用在医疗和调味中
It's also been used as medicine and flavoring
为糖果和酒品所用
for candy and liquor.
我打赌你现在心里所想的
I bet what you're thinking right now
不会是"好吃"  对吧
isn't "Yummy," Is it?
我想让你想的是
What I hope you're thinking is,
天啊  克莱真的是下狠心要知道
"Wow, Clay is serious about wanting to know
我把钱放在哪里了啊
"where I put that money.
我想我还是把账户号码给他吧
"I think I'll give him that account number now,
这样他就不会把我扔进这滩滚热的焦油里了
So he doesn't drop me into this vat of boiling tar"
抱歉  你说什么
I'm sorry, what?
中城银行账户  5463728
Central city bank account 5463728.
求你  求你  把我拉上去
Please, please, pull me up now.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry!
我记得你说过你不会杀了他
I thought you said you weren't gonna kill him.
我说过的话多了去了
I say a lot of things.
乔伊在哪
Where's Joey?
但愿他在别处
Wishing he was somewhere else.
咱们走吧
Let's go.
老兄  快上车  快走
Dude, get in the car! Let's go!
开车  开车
Drive! Drive!
现今
有一首歌的歌词我很喜欢
There's this song lyric I like.
世上所有破碎的心都依然在跳动
"All the broken hearts in the world still beat.
我的在跳动  但伤痕累累
"Mine's beating, but bruised.
希望不会太久
"Hopefully not for long.
我唯一知晓的是
"The one thing I do know is:
时间会改变一切
Time changes everything."
我没想到警察会见到这么多疯狂的事
I didn't think about how many crazy things police see.
并且印象深刻
And can't unsee.
你一直都想做个警察吗
You always wanted to be a cop?
是啊  我爸爸就是
Yeah, my dad was one.
他是我的英雄  所以
He was my hero, so
我从没想过去做别的
I never thought of being anything else.
你呢
What about you?
没有  我想去当宇航员
No, I wanted to be an astronaut.
等下  巴里也想做宇航员
Wait, that's what Barry wanted to be.
真的吗
Really?
估计不是因为一个原因
Probably not for the same reasons.
去宇宙是一个
Going to space is like the fastest
人类能达到的极速  所以不是宇航员
a human being can go, so it was either an astronaut
就是  你听说过超音速冲压喷气机吗
or, like, have you heard of scramjets?
好吧  它们就像是
Okay, they're like
燃烧氧气到达超音速  老兄
supersonic on oxygen, dude.
简直疯狂
It's nuts.
你说得对  和巴里的理由不一样
You're right. Not the same reason as Barry.
你真是对速度很痴迷啊
You are really all about the speed, huh?
是啊  那是我的最爱
Yeah, I mean, it's what I love.
所以你还在参加拉力赛
Is that why you're still drag racing?
你还在赛  对吧
You are, aren't you?
那不是有些危险吗
Isn't that a little dangerous?
是啊  对于和我赛的人来说
Yeah, for the people that race against me.
肯定危险
Sure is.
你看  感谢招待
Look, thanks for the hang,
但我得走了
but I got to go.
还很早  别走呢啊
It's early. Don't leave yet.
不了  我还有事情要做
No, I got some stuff to do.
改天再见
I'll see you later.
你干什么要那样
Why'd you do that?
感谢招待
"Thanks for the hang?"
他是你的儿子还是忘年交小伙伴
Is he your son or age-inappropriate buddy?
我知道这些互动有些奇怪
Look, I know the dynamic is weird.
但是我还在想办法呢
I'm just trying to figure it out.
从我的视角来看  就好像
From my perspective, it seems like
你在纵容某个会让
you're ignoring something that could,
我不知道  让沃利送命的事
Oh, I don't know, get Wally killed.
沃利能够想要了解我
The fact that Wally even wants to get to know me
就已经是场大胜利了  所以在今后
is the big win here, so in the future
你能试着别把他赶出家吗
could you try not chasing him out of the house?
爸  如果你要求我会照办
Look, dad, I'll play along if that's what you want,
但是你让他了解的是哪个你
but which you exactly are you trying to let him get to know?
因为我今晚看到的那个人
Because the person that I saw tonight,
我可没认出来  爸爸
I don't recognize that dad.
日志录入1-14:  乌龟人的大脑
Journal entry 1-14: Turtle's brain.
事实证明我对乌龟人大脑物质
So, what I learned from Turtle's brain matter
以及逆闪的了解
and the Reverse-Flash, as it turns out,
让我制造出这个装置
has allowed me to complete a device
把它放入闪电侠的战衣里
that when installed inside the Flash's suit,
我便可以控制他的速度  等他下次
will let me harness his speed, so that the next time
使用神速力的时候
he taps into the speed force...
我就可以开始...  收集速度
I could begin... collection.
我也希望有其他办法  可是没有
I wish there were another way, but there's not.
这么晚还在这里啊
You're here late.
你不也是吗  你不应该在外面...
As are you. Shouldn't you be out...
像26岁的小伙子周四晚上那样去潇洒吗
doing whatever it is that 26-year-olds do on a Thursday night?
我现在也是单身了
I am recently single.
所以我想我可以
So, I thought I would
来解决缺口问题
tackle the breach problem.
看能不能找到方法关闭缺口
See if I could figure out how to close them.
看来你也是这么想的
Looks like you had the same idea.
对
Right.
我一个人效率更高
I work better alone.
不  你难道没听过俗话说
Oh, no, haven't you heard the expression
"人多力量大"吗
"Two heads are better than one"?
没有
No.
那肯定是地球一上的
Must be an Earth-1 thing.
你知道  对我而言我的地球才是地球一
You understand, for me, that my Earth is Earth-1?
-知道  -你的地球还没造出
- Yeah. - Your Earth has yet to create
色味连锁相夸克物质
CFL Quark Matter,
所以要在科学上赶上我们
and so it would take you too long
你们得费很长时间
to catch up on the science haul.
我自己就可以了
Do it by myself.
这上面的科学
This science?
没错  那上面的
Yes, that science.
看好了
Watch this.
你真烦人
That's annoying.
好了  接下来的
All right, I'm all caught up
大约三十分钟所需要的我都学会了
or the next, like, 30 minutes, give or take.
好像我错过了这个
Looks like I missed one though.
好吧  你可以来帮忙
All right, you can assist,
可是得听我的
but I'm in charge.
好  听你的
Yeah, you're in charge.
你来这里干什么
What the hell are you doing here
别想送我去做治疗
aside from trying to send me to therapy?
告诉你了的  我有研究过
I told you, I did some research.
我觉得把这写进报纸
I thought it would be a good idea
会是个不错的主意  而且我也觉得
for a story for the paper, plus I thought this would be
这是我们俩增进了解很好的方法
a great way for us to really get to know each other.
我是说  我也想知道这有多刺激
I mean, I want to know what's so great about this
让你那么爱不释手  兄弟
that you can't let go, bro.
这里没人想
No one here is eager
看到自己的照片登上报纸  你懂不懂
to get their picture in the paper, you got me?
登上报纸的哪个版面呢
And which part of the paper?
是放收监照的
The front where they put
报纸头版  还是在背面的讣告版面
the mugshots or in the back in the obituary section?
你还是去从你爸爸的文件里
Yo, why don't you just take a page
找报道题材吧
out of your dad's book.
让我做我想做的  好吗
Let me do what I'm gonna do, Okay?
我不需要什么大姐姐
I don't need a big sister.
我知道  那你就得需要殡仪人员了
I know, you're gonna need an undertaker.
今晚最后一场比赛  各位
Last race of the night, people.
我们的卫冕冠军  尾灯
Our reigning champ: Tail Lights.
怎么
What?
不祝我好运吗
No good luck?
接下来将带来奥利弗·奎恩
We'll have the latest on Oliver Queen's
市长竞选的最新情况
Mayoral Campaign coming up.
本地新闻  屋顶沥青公司
In local news, Roofing Tar Industries,
在两年前尖端科研实验室的
which was devastated by the S.T.A.R. Labs'
粒子加速器爆炸中被毁
particle accelerator explosion two years ago,
目前终于要重新开张了
is finally set to reopen.
各位  走之前打扫干净好嘛
Guys, clean up before you leave!
两年了
Two years!
我被困在漆黑的地下
Two years I was trapped in the ground,
两年了
in that blackness.
什么都看不见
I couldn't see,
什么都感觉不到
I couldn't feel,
可憎恨不减
but I could still hate.
乔伊
Joey?
你们可曾想过被扔进
Did you ever wonder what it felt like
那滚烫的沥青桶里是什么感觉
when you dropped me in that vat of boiling tar?
我是被头朝下扔进去的
Since I went in headfirst,
我能感觉到耳朵和鼻子在燃烧
I actually felt my ears and nose burn off.
眼球灼烧的疼痛你无法想像
The pain of my eyeballs searing was unimaginable,
我试着呼吸  可喉咙也火热滚烫
but it was the way that it burned down my throat
那感觉真的无法言说
as I tried to breathe that I thought was really special.
求你
Please.
我让你也感受一下怎样
Why don't I just show you?
不好意思
Excuse me.
巴仔  你没事吧
Bar, you good?
没事  只是  你知道
Yeah, yeah, no, it's just, you know,
只是帕蒂不在有点奇怪
it's weird Patty's not here.
虽然原因不一样
Oh, not for the same reasons,
可我也很想念帕蒂
but I miss Patty too.
这里什么情况
What do we got?
受害者叫丹尼尔·伯治
Victim's name is Daniel Burge.
不是什么好人
Not exactly a boy scout,
但两年前买下了这间车库
but managed to buy this garage two years ago.
他看上去像是掉进了火山里
It looks like he was dipped in a volcano.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
实际上这烧伤痕迹的
Actually the depth and uniformity
深度和均匀程度看上去像是
of the burn pattern is something you would see
尸体被类似火山熔岩的东西包裹着
if the body was covered in something like lava,
但是低温烧伤
but with a lower burn temp
还有添加了某种化学物质
and an added chemical characteristic.
火因调查员并未发现其他助燃剂
The fire investigator didn't find a secondary accelerant.
是啊  他没有超能力肯定查不到
Yeah, he probably wouldn't with a meta.
好吧  我要带个样本回尖端科研实验室
All right, I'm gonna take a sample back to S.T.A.R. Labs.
让西斯科做个检测
Have Cisco run some tests.
好的  我去跟爱瑞丝吃午饭
Good, I'm gonna go meet Iris for lunch.
她想跟我谈谈沃利
She wants to talk to me about Wally.
对了  你和他怎么样了
Yeah, how's that going, you and him?
很好  还不错
Great. Well, good.
我也说不好  进步很小
I don't know, baby steps.
我想给他点空间
I'm trying to give him space.
毕竟他刚失去母亲
I mean, he just lost his mom.
刚见到我和他姐姐
Just met me and his sister.
他现在有很多事要考虑
He's got a lot on his plate.
是的  他刚找到世界上最好的父亲
Yeah, he just found the best dad he could've wished for.
你现在嘴里这么说
Oh, you say that now,
可你心里可不是这么想的
but you didn't always think that.
你以前太严厉了
Well, you were pretty strict.
这是可以肯定的
That's for sure.
不过严厉也未必不是好事
But strict isn't always a bad thing,
尤其是源于爱才严厉的
Especially when you know it's coming from love.
-一会再找你  -好的
- I'll talk to you later. - Yeah.
太肉麻了
It's disgusting.
好了  点这里
Okay, now click here.
怎么样  这就是我做的应用
Bam, that's my app.
看  这个应用就要启动了
See, the app just went live.
这样你就能收集到所有社交网络上
So, you can sink up all social media postings
关于超能力者的活动了
about meta-human activity.
要是有人在中城看到了诡异的东西
Somebody sees something cray in Central City,
我就能收到警报
I get an alert about it.
伙计
Yo, man,
你闲得太无聊了
you have too much time on your hands.
我还以为你会说这玩意很厉害呢
Oh, I thought you were gonna say it was cool.
你不能说我
I'm just saying, you can't judge me.
你女朋友不是刚把你甩了吗
Didn't your girlfriend just break up with you?
是的  的确如此
Yeah, pretty sure she just did.
哈里
Hey, Harry.
等等  这个应用能让你知道市里所有的事
Wait, so if that app gives you eyes and ears all over the city,
你为什么不用它来找你的梦中情人呢
then why don't you use it to find the next Ms. Right?
我是不是做了一个超能力者的社交神器
Did I just make the meta-human Tinder?
不行  不能有这种嗜好
Nope, not starting that fetish.
总是查看别人的资料
It's about checking your profile.
这里不能干那种事
This is not a place for that.
宝贝
Hey, baby.
你好像工作很努力啊
You look like you're working hard.
我就是很努力
I am.
我在研究一篇报道
I'm researching a story.
你一定会觉得很有趣的
One that you'll find interesting actually.
这是柯伦·罗伯茨
This is Curran Roberts.
之前他驾驶改装的高速汽车出了车祸
After his head went through the windshield
头撞出了挡风玻璃  昏迷了半年
of his hot rod, he was in a coma for six months.
这个小孩  他死了
This kid, he died.
他开车以将近180公里的时速
He wrapped his car around a tree
撞上了一棵树
at 110 miles per hour.
他们都是街道赛车手  老爸
They were all street racers, dad,
沃利可能就是下一个
and Wally could be the next one.
你想让我怎么办  爱瑞丝
What do you want me to do, Iris,
把他关起来吗
Lock him up?
可以取缔非法赛车啊
Or stop the races.
我很久以前就明白
Look, I learned a long time ago,
你永远改变不了孩子的本性
you can't stop your kids from being who they are.
是吗
Really?
你为什么不管教他呢  老爸
Why won't you be his parent, dad?
你在怕什么
What are you so afraid of?
好吧  你说得对
All right, you're right.
我是害怕
I'm afraid.
我害怕他会排斥我  排斥我们
I'm afraid he'll reject me, us.
就像我上次抓到他
Like the last time I confronted him
在赛车  我们不欢而散  还记得吗
about the races, it didn't go so well, remember?
我要对沃利态度好一些
And I need it to go well with Wally.
这么多年我们从没见面
I mean, after all these years lost,
我希望他能融入我们的生活
I want him in our lives,
但得先让我取得他的信任
But let me get him to trust me,
然后我才能实现这个目标
then I can do something about it.
好吧
Okay.
怎么了
What's the matter?
我忘了
I can't remember,
粒子的旋转和运动是同方向的
is the helicity of a particle left-handed
说明它是左旋的吗  还是相反
if its spin and motion is the same, or opposite?
-是  -等一下  我知道了
- It's... - No, hold on, I got it.
等等  别回答
Hold on, don't answer that.
相反  我就知道
Opposite. I knew that.
这样很烦人
You know that's really annoying?
我只是需要
It's, you know, just got to...
时不时重新
recharge the old short-term
补补脑
every once in a while.
这就像以前一样
You know, this feels like old times.
嗯
Okay.
我当然知道
Yeah, I mean, I know, obviously,
这是我们第一次一起工作
this is our first time working together,
可是我从你身上学到好多
but I am learning a lot from you.
之前那个威尔斯是个导师
The last Wells was a real mentor.
他坚信我什么都能做到
He believed that I could do anything.
也让我这么坚信
Made me believe it.
嗯
Okay.
他带我走进了新的世界
He opened up whole new worlds to me.
看来他真的像是我另一位父亲
Guess he really was like another father almost.
-闭嘴吧  好吧  -怎么了
- Stop it, all right? - What?
我没有求你来帮忙  好吧
I did not ask for you help, okay?
我更没有说要当你的导师
I certainly did not ask to be your mentor.
好吧  冷静点
Okay, relax.
我只是在说
I was just talking about--
你知道吗  我有自己的孩子
Hey, you know what? I have a kid already.
我不需要再来一个了  所以你滚吧
I don't need another one, so scram.
我自己来完成
Let me finish this by myself.
好吧
All right.
从周日以来我用六种方法检测了
Hey, I ran your crime scene samples
你的犯罪现场样本
six ways from Sunday.
你怎么了
What's wrong with you?
我刚才
I was...
没什么  怎么了
Uh, nothing. What's up?
两件事  很奇怪
Two things, very strange.
首先  焦油里的绝对是超能力者的细胞
One, definitely meta-human cells in the oil.
其次  他并不是死于烧伤
And two, he didn't die from his burns.
而是死于窒息
It was suffocation.
窒息
Suffocation?
检测到的氧气水平
发现超能力者细胞样本
还真说得通
That makes sense actually.
烧伤显示尸体被什么东西覆盖了
The burns indicated that the body was covered in something.
和有机物质的含氧水平交叉对比后
Cross-referencing O2 levels in the organic matter,
我找到了和在沥青泄露中被困住并保存的动物
I found a direct match to animals trapped
完全匹配的结果
and preserved in an asphalt seep.
这哥们被变成化石了
The guy was fossilized.
所以杀了他的那个人
So whoever killed him
就像是个行走着的
is like a walking--
-沥青坑  -沥青坑
- Tar Pit. - Tar Pit.
反应太慢了
Mmm, too slow.
没关系的
It's okay.
所以  他几乎是把他们淹死在沥青里
So, he's basically drowning them in tar.
天呐  简直是场恐怖秀
God, that's a horror show.
为什么他把丹尼尔·伯治作为目标
Why did he target Daniel Burge?
这是我的超能力者社交媒体应用
Oh, that's my meta-human social media App.
厉害吧
That's right.
现在有一起袭击事件
There's an attack in progress.
在第六大道和贝尔街的路口  市中心
6th and Bell, downtown.
还记得我吗  克莱
Remember me, Clay?
我们杀了你
We killed you.
我猜现在你不会在想
I bet right now you're not thinking...
"好吃"吧
"Yummy."
你们看到这个了吗
Yo, are you guys seeing this?
是的  我们看到了
Oh, yeah, we see it.
好的  有什么主意吗
All right, any ideas?
沥青的粘度随着温度降低而变低
Viscosity of asphalt lowers as its temperature lowers.
是啊是啊  而且它会变硬
Yeah, yeah, yeah, and it hardens.
想办法让他冷却下来
Hey, find a way to cool him down.
做烧烤的
Hey, barbeque!
有本事冲我来啊
Hit me with your best shot!
太棒了
Oh, yeah!
闪电侠队又得一分
Team Flash!
兄弟
Hey, buddy.
我有问题要问你
I've got some questions for you.
我们走
Let's go.
你要回家了  杰西
You're coming home, Jesse.
你就要回家了
You're coming home.
好的  所以这个沥青坑
All right, so Tar Pit--
我们现在这么叫他了吗
Tar Pit, that's what we're calling him?
-是啊  -沥青坑袭击的人叫克莱斯·坦利
- That's right. - Tar Pit was after one Clay Stanley.
而斯坦利  实际上
Stanley, as it turns out,
是中城警局一直以来
is a suspected hit man that the CCPD
在追捕一个职业杀手
has been trying to track for a while,
但他们没能坚持下去
but they haven't been able to make anything stick.
我不是含沙射影
No pun intended.
我们知道他被袭击的原因吗
Do we know why he was attacked?
斯坦利没有回答我的任何问题
Stanley wouldn't answer any of my questions.
他被吓坏了
He was pretty scared.
当一个杀手害怕的时候
When a hit man is scared,
你就知道事情不对头了
you know something's wrong.
你查出我们的这位超能力者是谁了吗
Hey, did you get an ID on our meta-human?
我正在五个不同的面部识别系统里
Yeah, I'm running it through five different
搜寻匹配结果
facial recognition systems right now,
所以应该只要一分钟
So it should take a minute.
找到了
And there it is.
谁是世界上最牛的黑客啊
Who's the best hacker in the world, people?
费利西蒂·斯莫克
Felicity Smoak.
你们俩什么毛病
What is wrong with you two?
一点也不友好
That's not friendship.
我们的超能力者叫约瑟夫·蒙泰莱奥内
Our meta-human's name is Joseph Monteleone.
他看上去很友善
Oh, he looks friendly.
中城警局 逮捕记录
泰莱奥内被报告为失踪的时间
Monteleone was reported missing
真是巧啊  正好是
aurprise, surprise, the night of the
粒子加速器爆炸的那晚
particle accelerator explosion.
那蒙泰莱奥内
And what's the connection
和两个受害者之间的联系是什么
Between monteleone and the two victims?
我打个电话给乔
I'll call joe.
让他调查下这三个人的背景
Have him run background checks on all three guys.
好  我去给焦油样本做点测试
Okay, I'm gonna run some tests on the tar samples.
看看我能不能找到他的弱点
See if I can find his weakness.
你今天感觉还好吗
Hey, are you feeling okay?
嗯  怎么了
Yeah. Why?
你比平时跑得慢了
You're going slower than normal.
你今天的时速是1450英里
You clocked in at 1,450 miles an hour.
不好意思  那我平时跑得有多快
But, I'm sorry, how fast do I usually run?
1500  你吃饱了吗
1,500. Are you getting enough to eat?
吃饱了  哥们  我真没事
Yes, yeah, dude, I'm fine, seriously.
这个差别小到可以忽略
The difference seems negligible.
还是很快  好吗
Fast is fast, right?
-再见  -好
- See ya. - Yep.
直接超车啊  你个白痴
Just overtake him, you idiot.
克拉克·布朗温
Clark Cronwen?
谁啊
Who's asking?
你就是那个在尾灯身边晃悠的女生
You're that chick who was hanging around Tail Lights.
我是《中城时报》的记者
I'm a reporter for CCPN.
我想要让你停止组织这些比赛
I want you to stop holding the races.
亲爱的  除非能帮我另找一份
Sweetheart, unless you could find me
一晚挣五千的活
another way to make five grand a night,
否则免谈
it ain't gonna happen.
这是我正在写的揭露稿的概要
Here's a preview of the expose that I am writing.
你是这篇报导的主角
You are the star of the piece.
中城街头
斗车的幕后黑手
我和你之前一些的合伙人聊了聊
I had a little chat with some of your previous associates
挖出了一些你的惊人内幕
and dug up some revealing details about you.
比如你领头的赌博团伙
Like the gambling rings you run
或者你参与的盗窃案
or the thefts you've been involved with.
我相信中城警局会对这个很感兴趣
I'm sure the CCPD will be interested in this one.
你忽视了一项罪名
You're forgetting something in here.
严重人身伤害罪
Aggravated assault.
你觉得只有你
You think you're the only one
会玩这一招吗
that can play this game?
我能查到你住在哪里
I could find out where you live,
吃些什么  什么时候睡觉
what you eat, when you sleep,
以及你生活中的每个小细节
every little detail about your life.
发表那篇垃圾文章
Publish that trash,
就等着看你的下场吧
we'll see what happens to you, hmm?
我已经录下
This entire conversation
整个对话  并发给了中城时报
is being recorded and sent to CCPN.
如果你或你的手下敢我一分一毫
If you or any of your people lay a hand on me,
我的同事会立刻把这段对话发给警方
my colleagues will send this to cops immediately.
滚出我的办公室
Get out of my office.
中城新闻图报
你有死亡愿望吗
You got a death wish?
你不是第一个这么问我的人  所以有吧
You are not the first person to accuse me of that, so maybe.
直接过去威胁他们
Going down there, threatening them?
爱瑞丝  这些人生活在暗处
These people, Iris, they live in the dark.
他们都是蟑螂  就算有人开灯
They're cockroaches, except they don't scatter
也不会散去
when someone turns on the lights.
他们就是想咬人
They're looking to bite.
如果他们这么危险  沃利
If they are so dangerous, Wally,
那你为什么和他们深交
then why are you in so deep with them?
我没有
I'm not.
只要我想  随时可以抽身
I can stop when I want.
那你为什么不抽身呢
So why don't you?
你说你玩街头赛车
You said that you were only street racing
只是为了赚钱付弗朗辛的医药费
to earn money for Francine's medical bills.
现在已经不需要付医药费了
Well, there are no medical bills anymore,
那你为什么还要玩赛车
so why are you still doing it?
听着  我不会因为你的原因
Look, I am not going to pretend
假装弗朗辛对我来说很重要
that Francine meant to me what she did to you,
但这段短短的时间里  我陪着她
but in the short time that I got to spend with her,
我看到了她的变化
I saw what kind of person she had become.
她聪明  善良和慈爱
She was smart and kind and loving,
我甚至无法想像你有多想她
so I can't even imagine how much you miss her.
你根本不了解我的感受
You don't know what I'm feeling.
那我告诉你我的感受吧
Well, let me tell you how I feel.
我知道你非常努力地
I know that you were trying really hard
让大家相信你是个坏蛋
to convince everyone that you were a badass,
但我知道你是个好孩子  沃利
but I know that you're a good kid, Wally.
单凭自己你是不会成长为这样的
And you didn't get that way raising yourself.
还有个单亲妈妈关心着你
You had a single mother who cared for you,
所以我和老爸关心你有没有撞树上
so my dad and I care whether you wrap yourself around a tree
有没有被流氓开枪打死
or get shot by one of these gangsters.
有人关心你的健康快乐
Having someone care about your well-being
对你来说不会是新鲜事
cannot be a new sensation for you.
你再去那里
Show up there again,
我就没法保护你了
and I won't be able to protect you.
只是再看看这些研究
Just going over some research.
十岁孩子的决心
Ten-year-old determination.
什么
What?
在我女儿十岁的时候
When my daughter was ten she...
科学老师叫她做份报告
Science teacher had her do a project, you know,
这份报告  我醒来的每一刻
and this project-- I spent every waking hour
都在修补完善她的太阳能烤箱
tinkering and perfecting her solar-powered oven.
十岁孩子的决心
Anyway, ten-year-old determination,
你让我想起了她
you remind me of her.
你也骂过她吗
Did you scold her as well?
骂过
Yes.
我知道这件事让你很难过
Look, I know that this has been hard for you,
但你并不是一个人在面对
but you're not in it alone.
是的  我就是一个人在面对
Yes, I am. Hell yes, I am.
我...尽管你们都很想我加入这个团队
I-- as much as you all want me to be part of your team,
但这是绝对不可能的
that's never going to happen.
我总会先从父亲的角度出发
I'm always going to be a father first.
总有一天  极速会逼我在你和我女儿之间
And one day, Zoom is gonna make me choose between you
做出选择  而每一次
and my daughter, and every time,
我都会坚定不移  毫不犹豫地选择我女儿
unblinkingly, unflinchingly, I would choose my daughter.
我会背叛你
I will betray you.
这是非此即彼的思想
That's binary thinking.
不必二选一
It doesn't have to be either-or.
生活就是二选一
Life is either-or--
是与否  黑与白  爱与恨
yes/no, black/white, love/hate--
从开天辟地直到现在都是如此
from the dawn of time to this moment right now.
看来我对你的信心
I guess I just have more faith in you
要远胜于你对自己的信心
than you have in yourself,
对了  我想到了一个办法
and by the way, I came up with an idea or...
或是一个想法
a notion rather,
关于如何永久关闭那些缺口
on how we could close the breaches for good.
这是
This is...
这是谁写的
this-- who wrote this?
你写的
You did.
是另一个你
Yeah, the other you.
邪恶的你  但是很聪明
Evil, not stupid.
我想答案也许
I think the answer might be
就在夸克物质的电磁绝缘子里
in the electromagnetic insulator of the Quark Matter.
我说了
Like I said,
我们是一个团队
we are a team.
我会仔细看看
I'm gonna take a look at this.
我会留下来
I'm going to stick around
用计算机二次离子质谱计算这个公式
and run some computer SIMS on the formula.
今晚见
I'll see you tonight.
晚点见
Yeah, see you later.
喝光
Drink up.
够吗
Had enough?
差远了
Not even close.
把我女儿还给我  我就把剩下的给你
Give me back my daughter and I'll get you the rest.
你没有资格跟我谈条件
You're not in the position to negotiate.
你不会杀我  也不会杀我女儿
You won't kill me and you won't kill my daughter
因为如果你这么做  就得不到你想要的
because if you do, then you won't get what you want.
我不需要杀你女儿
I don't need to kill your daughter.
但我可以折磨她
I can torture her.
只把她折磨得半死不活
Bring her right up to the edge of death,
我便可以不断折磨她
so I can do it again the next day
天天如此
and the next.
我要闪电侠其余的速度
Bring me the rest of Flash's speed.
我调查了这起事件中
I ran background checks
所有涉事人员的背景
on everyone involved in this tar pit mess,
没有任何发现
came up empty.
虽然有他们的记录
I mean, they all have records,
可都是密封的  我看不到
but they're sealed, so I can't read them.
那是因为你太循规蹈矩了  韦斯特警探
Well, that's cause you're bound by ethics, Detective West.
强行获取密封的法庭记录
How many felonies are we committing
我们会犯多少条重罪呢
breaking into sealed court records?
三或四条
Eh, three or four.
不  五条
Nope, five.
记录被密封
Well, they were sealed
是因为涉及到未成年犯罪
because the records are all juvenile offenses.
他们不是一起被捕的
They weren't arrested together.
不是  但看看这个
No, but look at this.
他们在同一家少管所服刑
They served in the same juvenile detention facility.
其实  蒙泰莱奥内和一号受害人是舍友
Actually, Monteleone and victim one were bunkmates.
那二号受害人的舍友是谁
Who do we have shacked up with vic two?
中城警察局  个人逮捕记录
布朗温·克拉克
Bronwen Clark.
找他可就难了
Good luck finding him.
他有一堆地址
He has a ton of addresses
而且我似乎找不到他现在的地址
and I can't seem to find anything current.
我给他的照片做个面部识别
I'll run his picture through facial recognition.
不需要了
That won't be necessary.
我认得这起案子里的人
In this case, I am facial recognition.
我知道在哪里能找到那个人
I know exactly where we can find that guy,
爸爸  你是不会喜欢这过程的
and, dad, you are not gonna like how.
你可以在路上告诉我
Okay, you can tell me about it on the way.
那是什么
What is that?
缺口内爆反应堆
Breach implosion reactor.
早知道就不问了
Sorry I asked.
你准备好了吗
You ready?
准备好了  走吧
Yeah, let's do it.
祝你们俩修复宇宙玩得开心
Have fun fixing the universe, you two.
哈里  怎么了
Hey, Harry. What's going on?
你看上去好像有点不舒服
You seem like you're in pain.
什么  不不  我就是...头疼
What? No, no, I have a...headache.
如果我们计算无误
If our calculations are correct...
-确实无误  -确实无误
- And they are. - And they are.
那么当这东西爆炸的时候
When this device detonates,
它将使缺口这边的视界
it will collapse the event horizon
轰然倒塌
on this side of the breach,
那么将永久切断与地球二的所有联系
thereby shutting off any connection to Earth-2 permanently.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
没事  我就是有点累了
Yeah, I'm just a little tired.
我状态有点不好
I don't feel like myself.
不过我没事
I'm good though.
-会成功的  哈里  -是的  好吧
- It's gonna work, Harry. - Yep, yep. Okay.
-准备好了吗  -准备好了  给我吧
- You ready? - Yeah, give it to me.
来吧
Come on.
我们做到了
We did it!
给点反应好吗
Come on!
你刚刚改写了物理定律
You just rewrote the laws of physics!
咋不笑一下给点反应呢
Don't smile or anything.
我想那很厉害吧
I guess that was pretty cool.
没错  当然
Yeah, I'd say so.
解决了一个  还有51个
One down, 51 to go.
艾伦
Allen...
怎么了
Yeah?
谢谢你
Thank you.
这只是救回你女儿的第一步
It's just the first step in getting your daughter back.
来吧
Come on!
欢迎来到底层社会的底层
Welcome to the wrong side of the wrong side of the tracks.
克拉克在哪里
So where's Clark?
那就是他
That's him.
快点
Come on, man.
那是沃利
There's Wally.
等我们的挥旗女郎准备好
Now, if our fly flag girl can step up,
我们就可以开始了
we're ready to begin.
什么...
What the...?
-打电话给巴里  -好的
- Call Barry. - Okay.
一切还好吗
We good?
关上缺口后你一直没说话
Been a little quiet ever since we closed the breach.
听着  艾伦
Listen, Allen...
不好意思  这是...  等我一下
Hey, sorry, it's...real quick.
我等下再回你  爱瑞丝  我...
Hey, let me call you back, Iris, I...
我要走了
I got to go.
爱瑞丝
Iris!
快带她去医院
Get her to the hospital!
亲爱的
Hey, baby.
你还好吗
You all right?
发生什么事了
What happened?
车上飞来的玻璃扎到你肩膀了
Piece of glass from that car pierced your shoulder.
但你会没事的
But you're gonna be all right.
我讨厌医院
I hate hospitals.
沃利  你好
Wally, hi.
我能进来吗
Hey, can I come in?
我给你带了一束花
I got you some flowers.
我不知道是哪一种  我就是...
I don't know what kind or anything, I just...
还是说你会过敏  她对花过敏吗
Or maybe you're allergic-- is she allergic to flowers?
不  我不过敏  沃利  谢谢
No, I'm not, Wally. Thank you.
那就好
Cool.
那我放这里了
I'll just leave them here.
没事的  沃利
It's okay, Wally.
早日康复
Feel better.
很快回来
I'll be back.
等一下
Hold up a minute.
我要去个地方
I got somewhere to be.
好啊  可以
Yeah, you do.
那就去你姐姐病床旁
At your sister's bedside.
爱瑞丝昨晚去那场比赛
Iris came to that race last night
是因为她关心你
because she cares about you.
听着  伙计  这不关我的事
Look, man, this ain't on me.
我没让她去看车赛
I didn't tell her to go to that race.
听着  我知道你没有
Look, I know you didn't.
我没有责备谁
This ain't a blame thing.
听我说完  好吗
Just hear me out, okay?
听着  我知道你刚刚失去了你的母亲
Look, I know you just lost your mother
而且你也是刚刚才发现我们的存在
and you just found us,
像龙卷风一样突如其来
it's been like a whirlwind.
现在  我无法告诉你该怎样生活
Now, I--I can't tell you how to live your life,
但是我可以告诉你  你并不孤单
but I can tell you this: You're not alone.
你拥有那些夜晚辗转反侧为你担忧的人们
You have people that sit up at night worried sick about you,
而且他们也不会停止对你的关怀
and they're not going to stop worrying about you.
这就是家的涵义
That's what a family does.
他们互相包容
They put up with each other
而且将彼此放在第一位
and they put each other first,
而不是先考虑自己
before ourselves.
那你现在不生我的气了
So you're not mad at me?
因为你对自己的生活太不负责了
For being reckless with your life?
是的  当然了  我对你很生气
Yeah, hell yeah, I'm mad at you.
但我对自己更生气因为我无法扮演一些角色
But I'm more mad at myself for being something I'm not.
我不是你的朋友  沃利
I'm not your friend, Wally.
我只是你的父亲
I'm your father.
我不会让你走的
I ain't letting you go.
好吧
Okay.
是巴里的电话
Oh, it's Barry.
去吧
Go.
我会留下来陪她
I'll stay with her.
你确定吗
You sure?
是的  她可是我姐  对吧
Well, she's my sister, right?
这才是我的好儿子
That's my boy.
别担心  我们会抓住他的
Don't worry, we're gonna get him.
抱歉  伙计  你说什么
I'm sorry, dude. What?
焦油坑
Tar pit.
你别担心了
You shouldn't worry.
我们可以用这些东西抓住他
We're gonna get him with these.
用这些含氮的榴弹
With these nitrous grenades.
每个榴弹都含有十倍于
Each of these has ten times
一个热力氮压罐的浓度
the concentration of a hot rod's nitrous tank
而且会被极高的温度触发
and is triggered by extreme heat.
我是说650度啊
We're talking 650 degrees.
这可是沥青的沸点
That's the boiling point of asphalt,
所以只要其中一个小东西被接通了
so one of these puppies makes contact,
你就能让他尝尝焦油冰棒的滋味了
you got a tar pit popsicle for dessert.
好吧  听起来不错
All right, that's great.
听着  我觉得或许你是对的
Hey, look, I think that maybe you were right.
今晚我感觉自己更慢了
I felt slower tonight.
你知道  虽然慢的不多  但也要命了
You know, not by much, but enough.
好吧  你觉得可能会不会是
Well, do you think there's something wrong
你的战袍出了点问题
with the suit maybe?
不太可能
It's unlikely.
战袍的读数是正常的
The readings from the suit are normal.
你知道的  我很关注这个
You know I take care of that thing.
好吧  那是怎么回事  难道我病了
Yeah, what? Am I sick?
我不知道  伙计
I don't know, dude.
你感觉到什么异样了吗
Feel any different?
没有  没什么不一样的
No, not really.
我的意思是  我知道某一刻我变得更慢了
I mean, I know that I'm slower in the moment,
但是我无法搞清楚究竟变慢了多少
but I can't tell by how much.
2%
2%.
你血液成分的检测结果显示
Tests on the components in your blood
你的神速力在过去的60天内  直到今天
show the speed force at a 100%
都维持在100%的水平
for the last 60 days until today,
现在降至98%了
it dropped to 98.
极速偷走了杰伊的速度
Zoom stole Jay's speed.
你觉得会不会
Do you think maybe,
在你跟极速打斗时
during your fight with Zoom,
你的速度可能就已经被削弱了
yours might have diminished?
但那都是几周前的事了
But that was weeks ago.
为什么我现在才感觉到那些影响呢
Why would I just be feeling those effects now?
-威尔斯博士  -怎么了
- Dr. Wells? - Yeah.
你对神速力的研究比谁都多
You've studied the speed force more than anyone.
你认为是怎么一回事呢
What do you think could have happened?
什么事都有可能
It could be any number of things.
是的  好吧
Yeah. All right.
我刚才去看了  我是说
I just looked, I mean,
爱瑞丝可能撑不过今晚
Iris could have died tonight.
她会没事的  巴里
She's gonna be okay, Barry.
你知道  就算这次她能逃过一劫
You know, this time,
但事实是  她现在受伤了
but the fact is, she is hurt
因为我
right now because of me.
今晚我的速度不足以去保护爱瑞丝
I wasn't fast enough to protect Iris
免受超能力者的伤害
just from some meta-human tonight.
如果极速再次发动攻击
When Zoom attacks again,
我需要用我全部的速度才能应对
I need all of my speed and then some.
我不能再失去任何人了
I can't lose anyone else.
你不会的
You won't.
是我干的
I did it.
什么
What?
那是什么东西
What is that?
我偷走了你的速度
I stole your speed.
并把它给了极速
I gave it to Zoom.
不不不  不会的
No, no, no, this isn't...
什么  你一直都在跟极速合作吗
What--you're working with Zoom?
不是  不是从一开始
No, not at first.
我们相信你  我相信你
We trusted you. I trusted you!
乔  住手
Joe, stop!
你为什么把他关在那儿
Why did you put him in there?
要是不这么做  我会杀了他的
Because if I didn't, I would've kill him.
我们去找那个焦油狂魔吧
Let's go find this tar freak.
-到底怎么回事  伙计  -闭嘴
- Yeah, what the hell, man? - Shut up.
我要被转移了吗
I thought I was being transferred.
你不是要被转移
You're not being transferred.
你是拿来当诱饵的
You're the bait.
什么
What?
这是为两年前你干的事  克莱
This is for two years ago, Clay.
呆着别动
Stay.
你知道的  实在是太讽刺了
You know, it's ironic.
就像我说过的
I was just saying
你让我想起了以前的那个威尔斯
how much you remind me of the old Wells,
现在我们来到这里
And now, here we are,
和当初我和他一样
Just like I did with him,
站在这面玻璃的两边
standing on either side of this glass
我在一边质问你  "为什么"
with me asking you, "Why""
我为了救我的女儿
I'm doing what I have to do
迫不得已如此
to save my daughter.
对  不惜任何代价是吗
Yeah, at any cost, right?
哪怕牺牲乔的女儿
The cost of Joe's daughter.
我说了  我会背叛你
I told you, "I would betray you."
我说了  我必须做出选择
I told you, "I would have to choose."
你选错了
You chose wrong.
错了吗
Really, did I?
我牺牲了我的女儿
Because I just sacrificed my daughter.
我为了救你儿子  让自己的女儿受死
Because I just sentenced my daughter to death to save your son.
你想让我安抚你吗
You want a pat on the back?
我想让你把我送回去
I want you to send me home.
送回地球二
Send me back to Earth-2.
考虑一下
Think about it.
极速想让你变得更快
Zoom wants you to get faster.
他想让你拥有更多神速力
He wants you to have more speed force in you,
只为最后夺走它  送我回去吧
for when he finally takes it, send me back,
用聚爆反应堆把缺口关闭
use the implosion reactor to shut down the breach.
关闭所有的缺口
Shut down all the breaches.
一举关闭
Close them all
那样极速再也过不来了
and Zoom will never be able to crossover,
再也不能
ever again,
然后这一切就结束了
and that'll be the end of it.
那你女儿怎么办
What about your daughter?
拯救杰西是我的责任  不是你的
Jesse's my battle to fight, not yours.
感觉怎么样了
How are you feeling?
能来点披萨就好了
Like I could use some pizza right now.
明天他们就放你出院了
Well, they're letting you out tomorrow,
到时候不管你想吃什么
So I can get you any kind you want
我都能满足你
from anywhere you want.
说定了
Deal.
知道吗  我小时候
You know...growing up,
我和妈妈没有很多钱
we didn't have a lot of money
去看电影或者买玩具
to go to the movies or buy toys.
取而代之  她会带我去兜风
Instead, she would just take me in the car,
我们就一路开着
we'd would go for these long drives.
只有我和她  伴着音乐
Just her and I and her music.
我记得和她在路上时
I remember being on the road with her
看着那些风景闪过
and just watching the scenery flash by
感觉那么快乐
and feeling so happy.
如今我赛车时
And now, when I race,
每次被那种速度包围
feeling that rush of speed,
就好像...
it's like...
就好像回到了过去的日子
It's like I get to back to those days.
我不想停下来
I didn't want to stop
因为如果停下...
Because if I do...
你看  这没有多难
See, that wasn't so hard.
其实真挺难的
Actually, it was pretty hard.
这是哈里对巴里造成伤害后
This is a sample of Barry's cells
巴里体内细胞的样本
after whatever Harry did to them.
你们可以看到  不仅耗尽了神速力
As you can see, not only is it drained of the speed force,
而且呈现出细胞染色体损害
But it's also presenting itself as chromosomal damage.
如果哈里继续对你这么做
If Harry kept doing what he was doing,
他将会永久夺走你的超能力
he could have taken your powers permanently.
连邪恶版威尔斯都没能研究出这个
Even evil Wells couldn't figure out how to do that one.
最好有人把他送回老家
Well, look, somebody better send his ass back
不然我要一枪打死他了
to where he came from or I'm gonna shoot him.
-阿门  -不行
- Amen. - No.
为什么不行
What do you mean, no?
如果处在他的位置
What would we have done
我们会怎么做
if we were in his position?
如果被抓的是爱瑞丝
I mean, what would you do
你会怎么做  乔
if it was Iris, Joe?
西斯科  史纳特绑架你时
And Cisco, when Snart kidnapped you,
威胁你要是不合作
threatened to kill your brother
就杀了你哥哥  你也合作了
unless you helped, you did,
我们都没有因此怪罪你
and none of us judged you for that.
现在也一样  因为一旦事情牵涉到家人
We still don't because when it comes to family,
牵涉到我们所爱的人时
when it comes to the people that we all love,
我们会变脆弱
we're all vulnerable.
我们谁都难免做出错误的决定
None of us are above making a wrong decision.
他完全可以做到
He could have done it.
他可以偷走我的速度
He could have stolen my speed,
一走了之
gotten away with it.
我们谁也无法察觉
None of us would have even known,
但他没有  现在他的女儿要死了
but he didn't, and now his daughter's gonna die
我们能说得过去吗
and we're okay with that?
我没法放弃她
I can't just give up on her.
我没法放弃那个世界
I can't give on a world.
那个世界里充满了面临死去的人
This is a world full of people who are facing death.
不知道  也许以我的速度难以打败极速
I don't know, I may not be fast enough to beat Zoom yet,
但我不准备就这样
but I'm not gonna just
关闭缺口  就这样算了
close the breaches and forget about it.
我们必须帮助威尔斯
We have to help Wells.
听着  各位
Look, guys, I...
是我最先信任了他
I was the one that trusted him first.
我承认
I own that.
我让他留下了
I let him stay
不顾你们所有人劝阻
when literally all of you told me not to,
所以目前为止所发生的一切
so everything that's happened up until this point,
都算我的
it's on me,
但这次必须我们一起决定
but this has to be a group decision.
来吧
Come on.
好吧
Well...
我猜是要说再见了
I guess this is good-bye.
不是的
No, it's not.
我说过我们是一个团队
I told you, we're a team.
现在你也是其中一员
Now you're a part of it.
我们要帮你救出杰西
We're gonna help you save Jesse.
我们不会让你一个人回去
We're not sending you through alone.
我们一起去地球二
We're going to Earth-2.